Guide to the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection PE.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Marxism I (17 pamphlets) (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Thomson, George. Marxism and Poetry. International Publishers, New York, NY., 1946 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Marxism in the United States With an Introduction by Albert Gates., 1947 (Box 73, Folder 2)
- Marxism II (15 pamphlets) (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Marx, Karl. Wage, Labor and Capital. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Pannekoek, Anton. Marxism and Darwinism. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., 1912 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Stalin, Joseph and H.G. Wells. Marxism vs. Liberalism: An Interview. International Publishers, USA., 1935 (Box 73, Folder 3)
- Marxism-Leninism (17 pamphlets) (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Marxism-Leninism (Box 73, Folder 4)
- Maryland (1 pamphlet) (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Maryland (Box 73, Folder 5)
- Mass Transit (8 pamphlets as well as fliers) (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - And Then Came TWU!. Transport Workers Union of America, New York, NY., 1950 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Cacchione, Peter. 5¢ Fare or 10¢ Fare Which is Fair?. Published by the author, Brooklyn, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Subways Are for Sitting. Communist Party of New York State, New York, NY., undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - The 5 Cent Fare in Danger. Civic Research Bureau., undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
- Massachusetts (2 pamphlets, as well as a constitution and party platform from the Communist Party of Massachusetts, fliers and brochures) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - A Confession of Faith. State Committee, Communist Party of Massachusetts., undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Reid, Willie Mae and Peter Camejo. The Racist Offensive Against Busing. Pathfinder Press, New York, NY., 1974 (Box 74, Folder 2)
- May Day I (9 pamphlets) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - May Day I (Box 74, Folder 3)
- May Day II (1 pamphlet and several fliers) (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - May Day II (Box 74, Folder 4)
- May Day 1930-1939 (1 pamphlet) (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Filley, Jane. An American Holiday. United May Day Provisional Committee, New York, NY., 1939 (Box 74, Folder 5)
- May Day 1940-1949 (19 pamphlets) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Attack Hitler Now! A May Day Call. New York State Committee, Communist Party., undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Day of Solidarity and Unity in Struggle. N.Y. District, Communist Party, New York, NY., undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Page, Myra. It Happened on May First. United May Day Committee., undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
- May Day 1950-1980 (15 pamphlets as well as fliers) (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - In Step with Working People Everywhere We March May Day. United Labor and Peoples Committee for May Day, New York, NY. (3 copies) (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - March for Peace. United Labor and People's Committee for May Day, New York, NY., 1952 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - May Day. Trade Union Committee 1959 May Day Celebration, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
- May Day 1980-1989 (3 pamphlets as well as articles and a poster) (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - May Day 1980-1989 (Box 74, Folder 8)
- Media (9 pamphlets) (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Brown, William Thurston. How Capitalism Has Hypnotized Society. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Jerome, V. J. The Negro in Hollywood Films. Masses and Mainstream, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Keracher, John. The Head-Fixing Industry. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., 1955 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Potamkin, Harry Alan. The Eyes of the Movie. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1934 (Box 74, Folder 9)
- Melish, Dr. John Howard and Rev. William Howard (2 pamphlets) (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - The Melish Case Challenge to the Church. Melish Defense Committee, Brooklyn, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - The Story of a Congregation Why the Melish Case is a Living Issue. Melish Defense Committee, Brooklyn, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
- Mexican-Americans (15 pamphlets) (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Gonzalez, Isabel. Step-Children of a Nation the Status of Mexican-Americans. American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, New York, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Morgan, Patricia. Shame of a Nation. Los Angeles Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, Los Angeles, CA., 1954 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Our Badge of Infamy A Petition to the United Nations on the Treatment of the Mexican Immigrant. American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1959 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - The Sleepy Lagoon Case. Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee, Los Angeles, CA. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Torrez, Lonrenzo. A Short History of Chicano Workers. Communist Party, U.S.A., New York, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Torrez, Lonrenzo. A Short History of Chicano Workers Part 2. Political Affairs Reprints, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - "Viva La Raza!" A Communist View on Chicano Liberation. New Outlook Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1970 (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Mexico (14 pamphlets) (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Douglas, Dorothy W. Mexican Labor A Bulwark of Democracy. American League for Peace and Democracy, New York, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Heriberto, General Jara. A Message from Mexico. Council for Pan-American Democracy, New York, NY., undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Strategy of the Communists. Workers Party of America, Chicago, IL. (2 copies), undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Toledano, Vicente Lombardo. 5th Column in Mexico. Council for Pan-American Democracy, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Toledano, Vicente Lombardo. The United States and Mexico Two Nations - One Ideal. Council for Pan-American Democracy, New York. (3 copies), 1942 (Box 75, Folder 3)
- Michigan (2 pamphlets) (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Albertson, William. The Trucks Act Michigan's Blueprint for a Fascist State. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1952 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - White, Walter and Thurgood Marshall. What Caused the Detroit Riot?. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Middle East I (23 pamphlets) (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Middle East I (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Middle East II (22 pamphlets) (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Middle East II (Box 76, Folder 1)
- Middle East III (8 pamphlets) (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Middle East III (Box 76, Folder 2)
- Militarism (22 pamphlets) (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Militarism (Box 76, Folder 3)
- Minnesota (1 pamphlet) (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Soltis, John Gabriel. Political Traitors and How They Work. Published by the author., 1924 (Box 76, Folder 4)
- Mississippi (2 pamphlets and a brochure) (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Hayden, Tom. Revolution in Mississippi. Students for a Democratic Society, New York, NY., 1962 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - M is for Mississippi and Murder. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, New York, NY., 1955 (Box 76, Folder 5)
- Missouri (1 pamphlet) (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Moving Forward. Communist Party of Missouri, St. Louis, MO., 1960 (Box 76, Folder 6)
- Mitchell, Charlene (1 pamphlet and an article) (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell, Charlene (Box 77, Folder 1)
- Monopoly (10 pamphlets) (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Monopoly (Box 77, Folder 2)
- Monthly Review (1 pamphlet) (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Monthly Review (Box 77, Folder 3)
- Mooney, Tom (18 pamphlets) (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Mooney, Tom (Box 77, Folder 4)
- Morocco (1 pamphlet) (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Morocco (Box 77, Folder 5)
- Mother Bloor (4 pamphlets) (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Mother Bloor (Box 77, Folder 6)
- Mozambique (1 pamphlet as well as brochures) (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Mozambique (Box 77, Folder 7)
- Mundt-Nixon Bill (9 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Mundt-Nixon Bill (Box 78, Folder 1)
- Munich (8 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Munich (Box 78, Folder 2)
- Muste, A.J. (1 pamphlet) (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Muste, A. J. Where Are We Now? American Radicalism and the Impact of Recent Soviet Developments. Liberation, New York, NY., undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
- Muntzer, Thomas (1 pamphlet) (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Muntzer, Thomas (Box 78, Folder 4)
- Namibia (3 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Namibia (Box 78, Folder 5)
- National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression (1 pamphlet) (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression (Box 78, Folder 6)
- National Council on American-Soviet Friendship (6 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - National Council on American-Soviet Friendship (Box 78, Folder 7)
- National Defense (7 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - National Defense (Box 78, Folder 8)
- National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (2 issues of The Bill of Rights Journal.) (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Box 78, Folder 9)
- National Labor Relations Act (3 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - National Labor Relations Act (Box 78, Folder 10)
- National Liberation (2 pamphlets) (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Volodin, L. On Internationalism and Nationalism. Soviet Booklets, London., 1963 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Winternitz, J. Nationalities in Europe. People's Publishing House, Bombay., 1945 (Box 78, Folder 11)
- National Question (8 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - National Question (Box 79, Folder 1)
- Nationalism and Colonialism (14 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Nationalism and Colonialism (Box 79, Folder 2)
- Nazism (13 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Herbst, Josephine. Behind the Swastika. Anti-Nazi Federation, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Miller, Moses. Nazis Preferred The Renazification of Western Germany. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1950 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Sholokhov, Mikhail. The Science of Hatred. New Age Publishers, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Simpson, Lawrence B. The 'Blessings' of Fascism My 18 Months in Nazi Hell. National Lawrence Simpson Tour Arrangements Committee, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - The Molotov Paper on Nazi Atrocities. The American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1942 (Box 79, Folder 3)
- Nazism: Labor (6 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Fighting Fascism in the Factories. Youth Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1934 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Hitler's Slave Markets. Soviet Russia Today, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Labor Under Hitler. The Research Department. Chest for Liberation of Workers of Europe, New York, NY., undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
- Nazism: Terrorism (11 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Nazism: Terrorism (Box 79, Folder 5)
- Nazism: Youth (4 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Hartshorne, E. Y. German Youth and the Nazi Dream of Victory. Farrar and Rinehart, New York., 1941 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Kuusinen, O. Youth and Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Wieden, Peter. This is Our Enemy. New Age Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 79, Folder 6)
- Nazi Spies: U.S.A. (4 pamphlets) (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Allen, Charles R. Jr. Nazi War Criminals Among Us. Jewish Currents, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1963 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Wakefield, Lowell. Hitler's Spy Plot in the U.S.A. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1939 (Box 79, Folder 7)
- Native Americans (6 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Talbot, Steve. Leonard Peltier and the American Ethnocide. World Peace Council, Helsinki., 1984 (Box 80, Folder 1)
- NATO (4 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - NATO (Box 80, Folder 2)
- Negro History Week (1 pamphlet and a supplement (2 copies) to Negro History Week published by the International Workers Order) (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Negro History Week (Box 80, Folder 3)
- Negro-Jewish Relations (9 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Negro-Jewish Relations (Box 80, Folder 4)
- Nelson, Steve (5 pamphlets as well as an article and a brochure) (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Shields, Art. Pittsburgh: Peace on Trial. Committee to Defend the Pittsburgh Frame-up Victims, Pittsburgh, PA., undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - State Sedition Laws are Weapons of Anti-Labor Anti-Negro Anti-Semitic Repression. Civil Rights Congress, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1955 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Steve Nelson: A Tribute by 14 Famous Authors. Provisional Committee to Free Steve Nelson. (2 copies), undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
- Neo-Colonialism (14 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Winston, Henry. New Colonialism U.S. Style. New Outlook Publishers, New York, NY., 1965 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Zhukov, E. M. Sharpening the Crisis of Colonial System After World War II. People's Publishing House, Bombay., 1950 (Box 80, Folder 6)
- Neo-Nazism (3 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Neo-Nazism (Box 80, Folder 7)
- New America (3 pamphlets) (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - New America (Box 80, Folder 8)
- New Deal (7 pamphlets and a brochure) (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Browder, Earl. What Every Worker Should Know About NRA. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1933 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Browder, Earl. What is the New Deal?. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1933 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Rochester, Anna. Your Dollar Under Roosevelt. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1933 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Take Your Choice. The Colored Division of the Democratic National Committee., undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
- New Mexico (1 pamphlet) (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - New Mexico (Box 81, Folder 1)
- New York City I (2 pamphlets) (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Ford, James W. Hunger and Terror in Harlem. Harlem Section, Communist Party, New York, NY., undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
- New York City II (23 pamphlets as well as fliers and brochures) (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Are Cops the Answer?. Communist Party of New York State, New York, NY. (4 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Calling All Tenants!. City-Wide Tenants Council, New York, NY., undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Ford, James W. Win Progress for Harlem. Harlem Division of the Communist Party, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Home or Slum Post-War Homes for Post-War New York. Citizens' Housing Council of New York, New York, NY., undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - MacMahon, Douglas L. Victory without Strike. Transport Workers Union, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Tyner, Jarvis. Koch's Corruption Scandal Crimes Against the People the New York City. Communist Party, New York State, New York, NY., 1986 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Why We Strike. Columbia Strike Committee., undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
- New York State (12 pamphlets, government document, reprinted article) (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Raymond, Harold. Dixie Comes to New York Story of the Freeport GI Slayings. Daily Worker, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Ross, Paul L. Ban Loyalty Oaths and Political Inquisitions in the New York State Constitution. Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
- New York State: CPUSA Writings (21 pamphlets as well as brochures) (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Green, Gilbert. New York's Wartime Election. New York State Committee, Communist Party, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1942 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Gerson, Simon W. It Is Happening Here. New York State Committee, Communist Party, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1941 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Krumbein, Charles and Israel Amter. Dollar for Democracy. (2 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - The House You Live In. Communist Party, N.Y. State, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - What New York State Needs. Communist Political Association of New York State, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
- New Zealand (5 pamphlets) (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - New Zealand (Box 81, Folder 6)
- Nicaragua (6 pamphlets) (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Nicaragua (Box 81, Folder 7)
- Nigeria (2 pamphlets) (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Nigeria (Box 81, Folder 8)
- Nixon, Richard M. (brochures) (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 81, Folder 9)
- Non-Violence (2 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Non-Violence (Box 82, Folder 1)
- North Carolina (3 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Braden, Carl. The Right to Organize How North Carolina Tries to Wreck People's Movements. Southern Conference Educational Fund, Louisville, KY. (2 copies), undated (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - North Carolina: Laboratory for Racism and Repression. National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, New York, NY. (Box 82, Folder 2)
- Nuclear Energy (4 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Nuclear Energy (Box 82, Folder 3)
- Nuclear War (9 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear War (Box 82, Folder 4)
- Nuclear Weapons I (19 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Weapons I (Box 82, Folder 5)
- Nuclear Weapons II (19 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Nuclear Weapons II (Box 82, Folder 6)
- Oceania (1 pamphlet) (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Oceania (Box 82, Folder 7)
- Ohio (10 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Ohio (Box 82, Folder 8)
- Oklahoma (4 pamphlets) (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Friessen, Gordon. Oklahoma Witch Hunt. Oklahoma Committee to Defend Political Prisoners, Oklahoma City, OK., 1941 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Oklahoma Story - 1940. National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, Washington, DC. (3 copies), undated (Box 82, Folder 9)
- Older Citizens (1 pamphlet) (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Older Citizens (Box 83, Folder 1)
- Olgin, M.J. (7 pamphlets) (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Olgin, M.J. (Box 83, Folder 2)
- Olympic Games (1 pamphlet) (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid. The Summer Games of 1980 in Moscow. Reprints from the Soviet Press, New York, NY. (Box 83, Folder 3)
- Pakistan (2 pamphlets) (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Pakistan (Box 83, Folder 4)
- Palestine I (15 pamphlets) (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Palestine I (Box 83, Folder 5)
- Palestine II (15 pamphlets) (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Palestine II (Box 83, Folder 6)
- Palestine III (12 pamphlets) (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Palestine III (Box 83, Folder 7)
- Palestine IV (17 pamphlets) (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Palestine IV (Box 84, Folder 1)
- Pan-Africanism (2 pamphlets) (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Pan-Africanism (Box 84, Folder 2)
- Paris Commune (14 pamphlets) (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Lenin, V. I. The Paris Commune. Lawrence and Wishart, London., 1931 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Marx, Karl. The Civil War in France. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Marx, Karl. The Paris Commune. New York Labor News Company, New York, NY., 1917 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Shachtman, Max. 1871 the Paris Commune. Daily Worker Publishing Company, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Siegel, William. The Paris Commune a Story in Pictures. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (5 copies, different versions), 1931, 1932, 1934 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Spiro, George. Paris on the Barricades a Story of the Commune of 1871. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1929 (Box 84, Folder 3)
- Patterson, William L. (3 pamphlets as well as newspaper clippings and memorial material) (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Patterson, William L. (Box 84, Folder 4)
- Peace I (30 pamphlets) (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Peace I (Box 84, Folder 5)
- Peace II (27 pamphlets) (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin, Herbert. A Program for Peace and Recovery. National Education Department International Workers Order, New York, NY., 1940 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Burton, Bernard. We Can Have Peace and Jobs!. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1953 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Clark, Joseph. Geneva Road to Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1955 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Dennis, Eugene. 21 Questions about War and Peace. Challenge, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1950 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Dennis, Eugene. Peace or War the People Against the Warmakers!. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Hart, Harold. The Cry for Peace. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Johannes Steel. The Case for Peace. Peoples Forum Publishing Co., New York, NY., undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Kahn, Albert E. Agents of Peace. The Hour Publishers., undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - The Road to Peace. Massachusetts Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Boston, MA., 1949 (Box 85, Folder 1)
- Peace III (33 pamphlets) (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Peace III (Box 85, Folder 2)
- Peace IV (9 pamphlets) (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Peace IV (Box 85, Folder 3)
- Peace: Appeasement (2 pamphlets) (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Peace: Appeasement (Box 85, Folder 4)
- Peace and Democracy (11 pamphlets) (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - 7 1/2 Million Speak for Peace... American League for Peace and Democracy, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1939 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Adams, David. The American Peace Movements: History, Root Causes, and Future. The Advocate Press, New Haven, CT., 1986 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Empowerment of People for Peace. Women Against Military Madness, Minneapolis, MN., 1984 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Rockman, Joseph. Broaden the Fight for Peace and Democracy. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1952 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Ward, Harry F. Fighting to Live. American League Against War and Fascism, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 85, Folder 5)
- Peace: Labor (7 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Labor's Stake in Peace. American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, PA. (2 copies), undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Peace and Solidarity. UAW International Affairs Department, Washington, DC. (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - The Yanks Are Not Coming. The Yanks Are Not Coming Committee, San Francisco, CA., undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
- Peace: Stockholm Appeal (1 pamphlet) (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Peace: Stockholm Appeal (Box 86, Folder 2)
- Peace: U.N. (6 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Peace: U.N. (Box 86, Folder 3)
- Peace: U.N. Speeches by Uyshinsky (10 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Peace: U.N. Speeches by Uyshinsky (Box 86, Folder 4)
- Peace: U.S.S.R. Proposals (21 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Peace: U.S.S.R. Proposals (Box 86, Folder 5)
- Peace: Women (18 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Beecher, Katherine. Wives or Widows?. Women's Division, New York Council, American Peace Mobilization, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley. Woman's Place - In the Fight for a Better World. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1947 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Hutchins, Grace. Women and War. Central Committee, Communist Party of the U.S.A., New York, NY., 1932 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores. The Women Want a People's Peace. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1941 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Millard, Betty. Women on Guard How the Women of the World Fight for Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1952 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Rivington, Ann. No Gold Stars for Us - Our Boys Stay Home!. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1940 (Box 86, Folder 6)
- Pennsylvania (8 pamphlets) (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Pinkowski, Edward. Lattimer Massacre. Sunshine Press, Philadelphia, PA., 1950 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - The Conspiracy Against Free Elections. Committee for Defense of Civil Rights of Communists, Pittsburgh, PA., undated (Box 86, Folder 7)
- Pension Plans (4 pamphlets) (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Bittelman, Alex. The Townsend Plan What It Is and What It Isn't. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1936 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - The $60 at 60 Pension Plan Minimum Security for Our Senior Citizens. Workers Alliance of America, Washington, DC., undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
- Pentagon Papers (1 pamphlet) (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - A Pentagon Papers Digest. Indochina Information Project, Los Angeles, CA., undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
- Perry, Pettis (8 pamphlets) (Box 87, Folder 3)